I'm Raymond Zeng. I work as a software
我是曾雷蒙德。我是做软件的
engineer making $306,500
工程师年薪 306,500 美元
and I live in the San Francisco Bay
我住在旧金山湾
Area. I'm going to be sharing all of my
区域。我将分享我的所有
finances between my bills and my
我的账单和我的财务之间
investments. This is Cost of Living.
投资。这是生活成本。
I'm a software engineer working at Meta.
我是一名在 Meta 工作的软件工程师。
In terms of my role, I earn $306,500
就我的角色而言，我的收入为 306,500 美元
on average.
平均而言。
After taxes and retirement
税后和退休后
contributions, I am currently taking
贡献，我目前正在接受
home about $4,000 a month.
家里每月大约4000美元。
I currently do not have any other
我目前没有任何其他
sources of income.
收入来源。
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> I work anywhere between 40 to 50 hours a
>> 我每年在任何地方工作 40 到 50 小时
week on average. In terms of my
平均一周。就我而言
day-to-day, it can be really anything.
日常生活中，它可以是任何事情。
My role is fairly dynamic, so I could be
我的角色相当动态，所以我可以
doing anything from software engineering
做任何软件工程方面的事情
and actual coding to some of the more
以及一些更多的实际编码
sort of project management or product
项目管理或产品类型
management stuff, as well as some data
管理的东西，以及一些数据
science [music] sort of analysis.
科学[音乐]类型的分析。
Prior to joining my current company, I'd
在加入现在的公司之前，我会
spent 2 years living in Dallas and I
我在达拉斯生活了两年
moved here about 7 or 8 months ago back
大约七八个月前搬到这里
in July of 2025. In terms of base rent,
2025 年 7 月。就基本租金而言，
I am paying $2,600 a month. Amenity fees
我每月支付 2,600 美元。便利设施费
are included in the base rent. Utilities
均包含在基本租金中。公用事业
will cost anywhere between $150 to $170
费用在 150 美元到 170 美元之间
a month. My electricity bill here is
一个月。我这里的电费单是
about 50% higher than it was in Dallas
比达拉斯高出约 50%
from about $20 to $30 per month to about
每月约 20 至 30 美元
$50 a month.
每月 50 美元。
I feel like I am getting good value. A
我觉得我得到了很好的价值。一个
lot of the comparable areas that are
许多可比较的领域
closer to my work could run anywhere
离我工作地点较近的地方可以跑
between $3,500 to $3,700 per month and
每月 3,500 至 3,700 美元之间，并且
I'm getting everything that I wanted out
我得到了我想要的一切
of this apartment. I live a little bit
这间公寓的。我住一点点
further away from either the major
远离主要
cities of San Francisco or San Jose or
旧金山或圣何塞等城市或
Oakland, but still within commutable
奥克兰，但仍在通勤范围内
distance of all three.
三者的距离。
Even though I had access to a relocation
尽管我有机会搬迁
expert, I decided to do a lot of the
专家，我决定做很多
research on my own taking a look at all
我自己研究看看所有
the things that I wanted to focus on
我想关注的事情
from a living perspective and after
从生活的角度和之后
making the decisions, I decided to sign
做出决定后，我决定签字
the lease sight unseen without actually
未实际看到的租赁景象
having seen the place in person. Hey,
亲眼见过这个地方。嘿，
welcome to my apartment.
欢迎来到我的公寓。
So, this is the main kitchen area.
所以，这是主要的厨房区域。
[music]
[音乐]
It's
它是
quite spacious compared to my last
与我上次相比相当宽敞
apartment. The only complaint that I
公寓。我唯一的抱怨
really have are these uh the countertops
真的有这些呃台面
aren't exactly ideal for the amount that
并不完全理想
I'm paying, but
我付钱了，但是
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> it's all right.
>> 没关系。
In terms of fridge and freezer,
就冰箱和冰柜而言，
I got some meal prep stuff from the
我从那里得到了一些准备饭菜的东西
night before as well as a whole host of
前一天晚上以及一大堆
uh drinks
呃饮料
and mixers.
和搅拌机。
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> Um
>> 嗯
in the freezer,
在冰箱里，
very similar thing where I've got a
非常相似的事情，我有一个
couple of frozen things as well as some
一些冷冻的东西以及一些
dumplings that I actually wrapped myself
自己包的饺子
when I was really bored one day.
当有一天我真的很无聊的时候。
Over here, we have my main sort of
在这里，我们有我的主要类型
living  workshop area. This is
生活车间区域。这是
where I get all my work done as well as
我在那里完成所有工作
my personal projects. The decision to do
我的个人项目。要做的决定
without a couch and a TV is really just
没有沙发和电视真的只是
based on my own needs. I don't really
根据我自己的需要。我真的不知道
watch a whole lot of TV. I just use my
看很多电视。我只是用我的
computer. I don't host people in my
电脑。我不接待别人
apartment, obviously. If I do decide to
公寓，显然。如果我决定
hang out with friends, I'll usually go
和朋友出去玩，我通常会去
to their place or maybe a third place.
到他们的地方或者第三个地方。
And in the case of hanging out with my
如果和我一起出去玩的话
friends in virtual reality, well,
虚拟现实中的朋友，嗯，
everyone sort of split off in their own
每个人都各自分裂
physical space. We've also got a couple
物理空间。我们还有一对
of other things over here, just uh
这里还有其他的事情，只是呃
the DJ controller because I really don't
DJ 控制器，因为我真的没有
have a lot of other space to put it, as
还有很多其他空间可以放置它，例如
well as my robot cleaner which gets the
以及我的扫地机器人
job done. It's not perfect, but it
工作完成了。它并不完美，但它
definitely helps out uh in terms of
绝对有帮助呃
having to clean.
必须清洁。
Over here, we've got just the bedroom.
在这里，我们只有卧室。
Haha.
哈哈。
I mean, there's really not much to my
我的意思是，我的东西真的不多
bedroom. It gets the job done for me. I
卧室。它帮我完成了工作。我
have my blanket, my pillow,
有我的毯子，我的枕头，
um
嗯
a filing cabinet doubling as a
一个文件柜兼作一个
nightstand as well as my charger there.
床头柜还有我的充电器。
It's all that I really need at this
这就是我真正需要的一切
point.
观点。
And this is my bathroom. The highlight
这是我的浴室。亮点
of this is really the bidet that I
这真的是我的坐浴盆
installed. It was about $400 or so, but
安装。大约是 400 美元左右，但是
it was a really, really nice quality of
这是一种非常非常好的品质
life improvement for myself.
为自己改善生活。
And outside over here, we've got a
在外面，我们有一个
little bit of a balcony.
一个小阳台。
I don't spend a lot of time out here as
我不会在这里花很多时间
you may be able to tell, but it is a
你也许能看出来，但这是一个
nice way to get some fresh air in.
呼吸新鲜空气的好方法。
I've been told by many of my friends
很多朋友都告诉我
that my living situation is very
我的生活状况很
spartan, but really it's an intentional
斯巴达，但实际上这是故意的
choice to pick and choose parts of my
选择挑选我的部分
life that I decide to spend more or less
我决定或多或少度过的生活
money on. So, even though my living
钱上。所以，尽管我的生活
situation right now is fairly sparse,
现在的情况相当稀疏，
that doesn't mean that it's going to
这并不意味着它会
stay that way say if I decide to have a
保持这种方式说如果我决定有一个
partner or have kids.
伴侣或有孩子。
Between ride sharing and public transit,
在拼车和公共交通之间，
I will sometimes spend around $30 per
我有时会花费大约 30 美元/次
month, but most of the time it's zero.
月，但大多数时候为零。
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> I live in the Bay Area without a car,
>> 我住在湾区没有车，
and so I think one of the big things to
所以我认为最重要的事情之一
me is [music] the accessibility to
我是[音乐]的可访问性
public transit. I live about 5 minutes
公共交通。我住5分钟左右
away from the nearest Bay Area rapid
距离最近的湾区快速
transit station. [music]
中转站。 [音乐]
I'm actually quite used to living
我其实已经习惯了生活
car-free. I had lived previously in
无车。我以前住过
Dallas for 2 years without a car and got
达拉斯 2 年没有车，得到了
around
大约
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> in very similar ways. I picked out this
>> 以非常相似的方式。我选了这个
apartment also specifically for its
公寓还专门为其
proximity to all of the things that I
靠近我所接触到的所有事物
would really want to go to [music] on a
真的很想去听[音乐]
regular basis. So, that would be cafe,
定期。那么，那就是咖啡馆，
boba shops, as well as the grocery
波巴店以及杂货店
store. [music]
店铺。 [音乐]
For those, I just walk and for anything
对于那些，我只是步行，为任何事情
else, I would either take the public
否则，我要么采取公众
transit or in certain cases [music] take
过境或在某些情况下[音乐]采取
ride sharing.
乘车共享。
Our company, like many other companies
我们公司和许多其他公司一样
around the Bay Area, have shuttles that
湾区周边有班车
go around the area and I utilize those
绕过该地区，我利用这些
to get to and from work.
上下班。
I spend about $300 per month on
我每月花费大约 300 美元
groceries.
杂货。
I usually budget $75 per month for
我通常每月预算 75 美元
eating out, but I usually don't hit that
出去吃饭，但我通常不这么做
maximum.
最大限度。
I used to get online delivery for my
我以前都是通过网上送货的
groceries, but not anymore given that
杂货，但鉴于此不再
it's so close to my apartment. I should
它离我的公寓很近。我应该
I should stock up on some more instant
我应该多储备一些即食的
noodles.
面条。
In terms of what I cook on a daily
就我每天做的菜而言
basis, I don't really have a set plan
基本上，我并没有一个固定的计划
because of the fact that my company
因为我的公司
subsidizes both my breakfast and my
补贴我的早餐和我的
lunch.
午餐。
But yes, beef short rib, 1434
但是，是的，牛小排，1434
or $10.99 per pound. This is a cut that
或每磅 10.99 美元。这是一个剪裁
usually isn't super widely available in
通常在以下领域并不广泛使用
western grocery stores. So, always nice
西方杂货店。所以，永远美好
to pick some up from the Asian grocery
从亚洲杂货店买一些
store.
店铺。
In terms of dinner, I'll usually meal
晚餐方面，我通常会吃
prep some sort of protein as well as
准备某种蛋白质以及
vegetables. So, it that could be
蔬菜。所以，这可能是
chicken, it could be some fish. Um it
鸡肉，也可能是一些鱼。嗯它
really just depends on my mood.
真的只取决于我的心情。
This herbal tea.
这花草茶。
This stuff This stuff is gas. Uh
这个东西这个东西是气体。呃
Also also a ton of sugar in there, but
里面还有一吨糖，但是
really really good.
真的真的很好。
Uh so, a pack of six for $3.99.
嗯，一包 6 个，售价 3.99 美元。
I'm lucky enough to be in a situation
我很幸运能够处于这样的境地
where food prices have not really
那里的食品价格还没有真正上涨
affected how I socialize or make these
影响了我的社交或制作这些的方式
decisions around food choices.
围绕食物选择的决定。
All righty. Let's go ahead and make our
好吧。让我们继续做我们的
way to the other grocery store.
去另一家杂货店的路。
Round two. Let's go.
第二轮。我们走吧。
In terms of cooking versus eating out, I
就做饭和外出就餐而言，我
am almost always cooking at home. I very
我几乎总是在家做饭。我很
rarely dine out.
很少出去吃饭。
Man, people are feening for the Coke
伙计，人们都在为可口可乐而烦恼
Zeros. They ran out of the of the large
零。他们跑出了大
ones.
那些。
Here's what I got at [music] the western
这是我在西部片[音乐]中得到的
supermarket. A loaf of white bread,
超级市场。一条白面包，
a bag of white rice,
一袋白米，
a dozen eggs,
鸡蛋一打，
a bottle of Coke,
一瓶可乐，
and
和
a gallon of whole milk. In total, this
一加仑全脂牛奶。总共，这
came out to [snorts] be $22.34.
结果[哼哼]是22.34美元。
Now, this isn't necessarily what I would
现在，这不一定是我想要的
get on a regular basis, but it's just to
定期进行，但这只是为了
give an idea of how things how much
大致了解一下事情有多少
things cost in my area.
我所在地区的东西很贵。
What do you do for fun in your free
闲暇时你会做哪些有趣的事情
time?
时间？
Uh that's an that's an excellent
呃，那是一个，那是一个极好的
question.
问题。
>> [laughter]
>> [笑声]
>> In terms of what I do in my free time,
>> 就我空闲时间所做的事情而言，
there are really three major areas that
实际上有三个主要领域
I spend my money on. The first is
我花我的钱。第一个是
finances, so really a lot about the
财务，所以真的有很多关于
credit cards and churning and that sort
信用卡和搅动之类的
of thing as well as my personal
事物以及我个人的
finances. There's also a big aspect of
财政。还有一个很大的方面
travel, whether that's domestic or
旅行，无论是国内旅行还是
international. And I am also an active
国际的。而且我也是一个活跃的人
participant in the furry community. I
毛茸茸社区的参与者。我
currently spend about $1,000 a year just
目前每年花费约1,000美元
for the privilege of owning the credit
为了拥有信用的特权
cards that I currently hold on to. In
我目前持有的卡片。在
terms of my hobbies, I generally spend
就我的爱好而言，我一般会花
between 4 and $500 a month across all of
每月 4 至 500 美元
them. Though in certain cases, I will
他们。尽管在某些情况下我会
spend a little bit more money and I'm
多花一点钱，我
currently saving up for a fursuit. On
目前正在攒钱买一件兽装。在
average, depending on where your maker
平均，取决于你的制造商在哪里
is as well as how reputable they are, a
以及他们的信誉如何，
fursuit will generally cost between 4 to
兽装通常花费 4 至
$7,000.
7,000 美元。
The furry community means a lot of
毛茸茸的社区意味着很多
different things to various [music]
不同的事物有不同的[音乐]
people. To some people, it's a way of
人们。对某些人来说，这是一种方式
expressing themselves, sometimes in
表达自己，有时
adult ways, and other times it's just a
成人的方式，而其他时候这只是
way of designing a fictional character
设计虚构人物的方法
and sort of
和有点
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> living in a bit of a mascot costume for
>> 穿着有点吉祥物服装的生活
a while.
一会儿。
To me, being part of this community
对我来说，成为这个社区的一部分
really means designing my own
真正意味着设计我自己的
characters, as well as embodying them in
人物，以及将他们体现在
the form of either commissioning art or
委托艺术的形式或
in some extreme cases, commissioning
在某些极端情况下，调试
fursuits.
兽装。
And all of this faux fur, or at least
所有这些人造毛皮，或者至少
part of it, will eventually end up on
它的一部分，最终将结束于
the head.
头。
Um [music] this is a bigger part of the
嗯[音乐]这是更大的一部分
project, especially since I'm not super
项目，特别是因为我不是超级
familiar with sewing, but it'll
熟悉缝纫，但它会
eventually end up on there. So, my
最终到达那里。所以，我的
character currently is a bit of a cyborg
目前的角色有点像机器人
hybrid between a canine as well as a
犬科动物和
robot, known in the community
机器人，在社区中众所周知
colloquially as a protogen.
通俗地称为质原。
I think
我认为
for for really anything mentioning
对于任何提及的事情
[music] furry in in the furry community
[音乐] 毛茸茸的社区里的毛茸茸
as well, because of it being a sort of
同样，因为它是一种
historically marginalized community in
历史上被边缘化的社区
the social space, there are a lot of
社交空间，有很多
concerns around um doxxing as well as in
围绕嗯人肉搜索以及
general people not necessarily being
一般人不一定是
super comfortable with being public with
与公众相处超级舒服
this. I just happen to be one of the
这。我只是碰巧是其中之一
stupid people that decided to go public
愚蠢的人决定公开
with this.
有了这个。
I don't really spend a lot of money on
我真的没有花很多钱
improving my finances. It's more so of a
改善我的财务状况。这更像是一个
lifestyle choice to take a look at
生活方式选择看看
credit cards and the perks that they
信用卡及其福利
offer and whether or not it's really
报价以及是否真的
worth it to me. In terms of maximizing
对我来说值得。在最大化方面
your value for the points, this is
您的积分价值是
really a process of trying to earn those
这确实是一个努力赢得这些的过程
points in the most efficient way and
以最有效的方式进行积分
spending [music] those points in the
花费[音乐]这些点
most efficient way. Generally, in terms
最有效的方式。一般来说，就
of earning, you're going to be getting
的收入，你将会得到
those from sign-up bonuses rather than
那些来自注册奖金而不是
everyday spend. And in terms of actually
日常花费。而就实际而言
cashing in those points, you're going to
兑现这些积分，您将
be trying to look for value where, say,
试图寻找价值，比如说，
maybe a business class ticket might be
也许商务舱机票可能是
$5,000 but only $2,500 worth of points.
5,000 美元，但积分仅价值 2,500 美元。
[music]
[音乐]
I was fortunate enough to grow up in a
我很幸运能够成长在一个
household where my mother was very
我母亲非常喜欢的家庭
financially illiterate. And she was
财务文盲。而她是
actually the one that got me interested
实际上是让我感兴趣的
in credit cards and churning in the
在信用卡和搅动
first place. The most recent trip that I
首位。我最近的一次旅行
did was to Southeast Asia, so Singapore
去了东南亚，所以新加坡
as well as Malaysia. I was fortunate
还有马来西亚。我很幸运
enough to bring my dad along as well as
足够带我爸爸一起去
my sister.
我的姐妹。
I have health insurance provided by my
我有我的健康保险
employer. I am currently paying for a
雇主。我目前正在支付
high deductible plan and I spend about
高免赔额计划，我花费大约
$17 per month. I currently do not have
每月 17 美元。我目前没有
any recurring health care costs. In
任何经常性的医疗保健费用。在
terms of staying fit, my apartment has a
就保持健康而言，我的公寓有一个
gym, but in case I'm lazy to do that, I
健身房，但以防万一我懒得这么做，我
also do body weight fitness. And for
也做体重健身。而对于
cardio and aerobics, I do dancing.
有氧运动和有氧运动，我跳舞。
One of the big parts about the furry
关于毛茸茸的重要部分之一
conventions are as well are the the
惯例也是
raves that happen in person. And there
亲自发生的狂欢。还有那里
are some people there are that know how
有人知道如何做吗
to dance.
跳舞。
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> In any given month, I will save anywhere
>> 在任何特定的月份，我都会​​在任何地方存钱
between $5,000 to $20,000. In terms of
5,000 美元至 20,000 美元之间。按照
that large range, it really depends on
这么大的范围，这实际上取决于
whether or not my 401k is maxed out,
无论我的 401k 是否已满，
whether or not I have any stock vesting,
无论我是否有任何股票归属，
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> and whether or not I have any bonuses.
>> 以及我是否有任何奖金。
In terms of maxing out my 401k with my
就用我的 401k 最大化而言
employer, I contribute $24,500
雇主，我贡献 $24,500
up to the maximum limit that I can
达到我能做到的最大限制
contribute alongside my employer
与我的雇主一起做出贡献
contributions.
贡献。
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> In addition to that, I make after-tax
>> 除此之外，我还做税后
contributions all the way up to the IRS
一直到美国国税局 (IRS) 的捐款
limit of $72,000. [music] So, in total,
限额为 72,000 美元。 [音乐] 所以，总的来说，
about 1/6 of my compensation is going
我的报酬的大约 1/6 用于
towards my 401k. In terms of my other
迈向我的401k。就我的其他方面而言
investments, I also max out my Roth IRA
投资，我也最大化了我的 Roth IRA
and HSA every single year, and then any
和 HSA 每年，然后任何
additional money goes into my brokerage
额外的钱进入我的经纪业务
account. I'm currently about 80%
帐户。我目前大约80%
invested in the US stock market and 20%
投资美国股市20%
internationally.
国际上。
I think like with many other parts of my
我认为就像我的许多其他部分一样
generation, there is very much a big
一代人，有很大
split in terms of financial literacy
金融知识方面的分歧
among other things. There's a swath of
除其他事项外。有一大片
people who are fairly well educated in
受过良好教育的人
terms of personal finances, and there
个人财务方面，还有
are a lot of those who are just getting
很多人刚刚获得
by. I view personal finance in a very
经过。我非常看重个人理财
similar way as I do personal fitness. A
与我个人健身的方式类似。一个
lot of the core concepts are fairly
很多核心概念都相当
simple, but it doesn't mean that it's
很简单，但这并不意味着它是
easy to follow and there are a lot of
很容易遵循并且有很多
traps along the way. I'm aiming to
一路上的陷阱。我的目标是
retire by the age of 30, in which case
30岁之前退休，在这种情况下
I'll need about 1.6 million dollars to
我需要大约 160 万美元
do so. In terms of why I decided to
这样做。至于我决定的原因
start pursuing the path of financial
开始走金融之路
independence and retiring early, I
独立并提前退休，我
wanted to build a life for myself where
想为自己创造一种生活
I wouldn't have to work for money all
我不必为了钱而工作
the way up until 65.
一直到65。
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> There's a lot of moving parts when it
>> 有很多活动部件
comes to retirement planning and even
涉及退休计划，甚至
establishing a goal number is a bit of a
设定一个目标数字有点困难
moving goal post in general. The rule of
一般情况下移动球门柱。的规则
thumb in the community is to multiply
社区中的大拇指就是倍增
your expenses by 25, or otherwise known
您的开支 25 岁或以其他方式已知
as the 4% rule, and if you're retiring
按照 4% 规则，如果你要退休
earlier than say around 40 or so, you
早于说大约 40 左右，你
might want to add some leeway to that.
可能想为此添加一些余地。
And so my budget is a little bit greater
所以我的预算有点多
than the actual 4% rule.
比实际的 4% 规则。
There's a lot of different projections
有很多不同的预测
in terms of how much I'm going to be
就我将要达到的程度而言
contributing in the future, as well as
以及对未来的贡献
how well the stock market is going to do
股市表现如何
over that course of time.
在那段时间里。
I have way too many sheets in this uh in
我这里面有太多的床单了
this. So, every month I'll create a copy
这。所以，每个月我都会创建一个副本
of this sort of base spreadsheet. I
此类基本电子表格。我
designed it myself. I don't really have
我自己设计的。我真的没有
a template that I follow, and I prefer
我遵循并且更喜欢的模板
it this way. It's more of a DIY approach
就这样。这更像是一种 DIY 方法
of if I decide that there are certain
如果我决定有某些
categories that I don't want, or
我不想要的类别，或者
categories that I do need, then I'll
我确实需要的类别，然后我会
[music] just add it onto the spreadsheet
[音乐]只需将其添加到电子表格中即可
and it'll be copied over for the
它将被复制到
remainder of however long I decide to do
无论我决定做什么，剩下的时间
this budgeting. [music]
这个预算。 [音乐]
I actually do have a larger tax sheet
我实际上有一张更大的税表
that does track down in terms of like
这确实可以追踪类似的情况
>> [music]
>> [音乐]
>> taxes that I'm paying
>> 我缴纳的税款
in terms of the income that I'm getting,
就我获得的收入而言
the expected amount of paychecks, and
预期的薪水金额，以及
then over here I just have some pretty
然后我这里有一些漂亮的
straightforward projections in terms of
直接预测
actually where I'm going to be at
实际上我要去的地方
financially for a given year and age
特定年份和年龄的经济状况
assuming certain figures [music] for
假设某些数字[音乐]为
growth as well as investment outcome.
增长以及投资成果。
And yeah, so by age 30 assuming that all
是的，所以到 30 岁时，假设所有
goes well, I'm expecting that I might
进展顺利，我期待着我可能
have somewhere north of around $2
有大约 2 美元以北的地方
million invested.
投资万元。
And this is also tracking the active
这也在跟踪活跃的
price of some of my investments, and so
我的一些投资的价格等等
this will fluctuate over time. And by
这会随着时间的推移而波动。并由
age 40, I'm expected to be retired at
40岁，我预计退休年龄
that point, so I do have empty columns
那一点，所以我确实有空列
in terms [music] of my actual
就我实际的[音乐]而言
investments.
投资。
But at that point, I might have
但到那时，我可能会
somewhere in the north of $7 million
700万美元以上
invested.
投资。
I think a very interesting part of the
我认为其中一个非常有趣的部分
FIRE community is that it has splintered
FIRE 社区已经分裂
off into various groups and evolved from
分成不同的群体并演化而来
its original form around the 2010s that
它的最初形式是在2010年代左右
was largely focused on frugality at all
主要关注节俭
costs. [music] Now there are folks such
成本。 [音乐] 现在有这样的人
as myself that sort of can have their
像我这样的人可以有他们的
cake and eat it, too, where we are able
蛋糕也可以吃，只要我们有能力
to live a very fulfilling lifestyle and
过上非常充实的生活方式并且
save a lot for retirement. In terms of
为退休储蓄很多。按照
my lifestyle after retirement, I don't
我退休后的生活方式，我不
expect that I'm going to stop working
预计我会停止工作
entirely. I might pick up some odd jobs
完全。我可能会做一些零工
or contracting work every now and then
或时不时地承包工作
just if I decide that it's interesting
只要我认为这很有趣
to me. Other than that, it's really
大部头书。除此之外，真的是
going to be populated with travel as
将会充满旅行
well as attending conventions and just
以及参加会议和只是
being myself.
做我自己。
I think one of the biggest privileges
我认为最大的特权之一
[music] for myself is that I am able to
[音乐]对于我自己来说，我能够
earn enough of an income where I could
尽我所能赚取足够的收入
reasonably support my family if they
合理地支持我的家人，如果他们
were ever in trouble, and in the case of
曾经遇到过麻烦，并且在这种情况下
a future family, that would be something
未来的家庭，那将是
that I would have to readjust over time.
随着时间的推移我必须重新调整。
Moving here has definitely been worth
搬到这里绝对是值得的
it. Even though the cost of living is
它。尽管生活成本
higher, the job compensation and the
更高的工作报酬和
opportunities available here are really
这里提供的机会确实很多
unmatched. In terms of staying here
无与伦比的。就住在这里而言
long-term, I'm
从长远来看，我
That's that that that's a that's an
那是那个 那是一个 那是一个
existential question.
存在主义问题。
>> [laughter]
>> [笑声]
>> Uh
>> 呃
I think in terms of long-term living, I
我认为从长期生活的角度来看，
plan to move back to the Los Angeles
计划搬回洛杉矶
area.
区域。
I could definitely see myself in the
我绝对可以在其中看到自己
position of starting a company in the
创办公司的职位
next couple of years or decades, but no
未来几年或几十年，但不会
plans for that currently.
目前的计划。
My biggest piece of advice is something
我最大的建议是
that's fairly widely shared among the
这是相当广泛的共享
folks in the FIRE community, and it's
FIRE 社区的人们，
build a life you want and then save for
建立你想要的生活，然后为之存钱
it.
它。
There may be a situation where you can't
可能有一种情况你不能
have everything all at once [music] now,
现在一切都齐备了[音乐]，
and you just kind of have to pick and
你只需要选择
choose whether or not you want to live
选择你是否想活下去
in a favorable location, or you decide
在一个有利的位置，或者你决定
[music] to spend more on say travel and
[音乐] 在旅行上花费更多
other experiences, or maybe on some of
其他经历，或者也许是某些
the other material goods that you're
你所拥有的其他物质商品
looking at.
看着。
Oh man.
噢，伙计。
I'm going to I'm going to get roasted by
我要被烤了
so many people. It's going to be the the
这么多人。这将是
people who who are going to comment on
即将发表评论的人
my forum, the people who are going to
我的论坛，那些要去的人
comment on the furry thing, the people
评论毛茸茸的东西，人们
that are going to comment on my
将对我的评论
apartment.
公寓。